Marvelous Designer has updated five new features in 2025.
It's all about improving the reality of clothing design,
working efficiency and creative performance.
Let's learn about the updated content together.
New attribute key pins
Now you can create key pin animations
for more content such as version attributes,
accessories and fake sewing needles.
Through these new key pin animations,
we have created the following demonstration content for you.
We created a inflatable animation for the little robot.
In order to achieve this effect,
we first need to use the attribute of the first new key pin animation,
the shrink.
We will increase the
shrink and shrink at the end of the version,
making the fabric wrapped around the robot larger in level and vertical direction.
Next is to adjust the pressure.
By adding key pins to the pressure value to gradually increase,
our robot will be able to
achieve the inflatable effect.
You can use the key pin to set the positive and negative pressure
to deeply present the inflatable or compressed animation process.
By adding key pins to the shape optimization,
you can control the fabric
to keep the wrinkle shape when recording animation.
We will use this function
to keep the wrinkle shape after the robot inflates,
so that it reduces the excess wrinkle when moving.
In another example,
when we jump,
we use the shirt and increase the strength of the shape optimization,
so that it reduces the effect of the movement.
It is better to keep the shape in the swing.
In order to show the animation of the key pin,
we will sew a small ball into the robot's hand,
and at the same time increase the strength of the sewing needle,
and reduce the wrinkle effect,
so that the ball falls to the ground.
But don't worry,
we will return the ball to the little robot.
We will use the last new key pin attribute,
the negative weight.
Since the ball body is a negative key,
we can instantly reduce its weight through the key pin at the moment it touches the ground.
we can instantly reduce its weight through the key pin,
so that the ball becomes lighter,
and the negative wind will pull it back into the robot's hand.
Change the key pin
The key pin can now be turned into a key pin or a virtual model accessory.
This feature will make it easier for you to create and manage these materials in Marvelous Designer,
to build a reusable accessory box,
and design and create with hard surface.
To show the advantages of this feature,
we use the creation butterfly accessory as an example.
First, we use the conventional key pin production method to make a butterfly shape.
Then, we can convert it into a key pin and add it to the suit.
After converting to a key pin,
the butterfly no longer participates in physical simulation in the form of clothing.
This will save computing resources and improve efficiency.
The other advantage of this feature is that it can be created directly in Marvelous Designer.
such as plastic, wood or metal objects.
The metal armor on this armor was originally made in the form of clothing cloth,
and then converted to a key pin.
As a key pin, it can be kept rigid and will not deform during simulation.
You can use the armor tool to fix the key pin on the suit.
With this new feature,
we can create a meaningful armor knight.
In addition, we can now convert the suit into a virtual model configuration.
With the long sleeve of the knight,
first convert it into a configuration and select the appropriate type.
After that, you can easily add the long sleeve to the new virtual model
and apply it to other projects.
To export FBX,
in the previous version,
the files optimized through the Everywhere function
need to be uploaded to the Connect platform.
To export FBX files,
you can now directly optimize the local resources and export FBX files.
The latest option is to replace the original Connect option.
The location remains unchanged.
The specific steps are as follows.
Open Everywhere,
optimize the clothing file,
bind the skeleton,
fill in the UV,
and prepare the sticker.
After completing the above optimization steps,
you can select to export the file as an FBX file
to the local file folder.
MetaHuman
MetaHuman with DNA format
can now be imported into Marvelous Designer as a virtual model.
MetaHuman with DNA format can now be imported into Marvelous Designer as a virtual model.
Through the new workflow,
users can directly import the MetaHuman model
into Marvelous Designer
and will not lose any data information
so that you can make clothes for MetaHuman seamlessly.
After completing the production in Marvelous Designer,
you can return all the content to MetaHuman Creator.
At this time, the clothing will be automatically adjusted according to the body type of the character.
This compatibility enhancement
makes it easy for MetaHuman to create high-quality BG clothing
and become unprecedented convenience.
Handmade tools
are often time-consuming tools
and usually require precise calculations.
The newly introduced handmade tools
can be adjusted to the exact size
by the intuitive interface
so that you can easily add a knife,
a bow,
and a seal to the version.
This completely changes the traditional mode
that relies on manual calculations and adjustments
so that you can invest more time
into clothing design and folding.
If you are not satisfied with the effect,
you only need to cancel one item
and you can immediately adjust the version in the menu.
You don't need to change it again and again.
With more options and simpler steps,
it will become easier and more convenient
to add clothes such as couplets, half-body dresses, and costumes.
Come and update to the 2025.2 version
and experience the five major updates and other highlights yourself.
To learn more information,
please browse the official website
or check out the video content of subsequent updates.